[Music]
Hello, everyone.
TDSW YouTube Channel.
This will be the tenth episode of Getting started with GLSL on TouchDesigner.
Thank you for watching!
This time, in response to the TOP you're looking at right now, we're going to use
We will make one that is rotating and scaling
We use Ramp TOP's Radial for our in-betweens.
In the third installment, I was scaling up and down by putting a float on uv.
We'll use the matrix here.
What we're going to do this time.
First of all, the rotation with the matrix.
Further scaling with matrices
Those are the two points.
So let's get to it.
This time, sir.
We'll start with this ramp as an input
Ramp has a 720x720 resolution.
This is a 1280x720
Input to this GLSL TOP
And here's the thing.
Since we are normalizing from -1 to 1
Zero is the center point.
Here it is.
So here's how it works.
It's going to be placed here like 0 to 1
It's a queue at GLSL.
You can use three types, mat2, mat3, and mat4, and
These are used in conjunction with vector
I have to warn you, though.
vec2 when using mat2 and vec3 when using mat3
And so on.
You'll need to use the last number together
As far as the matrix is concerned in this series.
I'm just trying to use it for now.
We'll do this while we look at this page in The Book of Shaders
Right here.
Here is a simple translate first
You don't have to use the queue to do this.
I'm not going to cover it this time.
Here's the spin of the shank
There's a formula in the rotation section.
This is the formula for the rotation matrix
And you know what?
This expression can be expressed like this on GLSL
Let's write a little bit about this.
This time we'll start from the beginning and write it as a function
mat2 rotate2d(float angle)
return mat2
cos(angle)
-sin(angle)
sin(angle)
cos(angle)
Okay.
I'm getting an error and would like to fix it.
That's fixed.
The function has now been declared
We will use this in the main function
Usage.
Multiply this p by the function you created
rotate2d()
I want to add some movement to this one too.
I'd like to put in some time.
Not yet, of course.
Declare it here.
If you put in Load Uniform Names, you can use the
I'm not in it.
Let's just write it down.
If you put something like absTime.frame in here, you can put
Oh, you're not doing it right here.
Like this.
It's so fast.
I'm going to slow this down a bit.
This is how I can rotate now.
That's the central point of this GLSL right now.
There's been a rotation.
This is normalized from -1 to 1, so
The rotation is supposed to take place in the center of the whole
Let's look at this in uv.
It's like this.
That the 0's revolve around here and here.
That's what it looks like.
This one, sir.
If you want to turn this input in the center of the image, you can use
Before this rotation.
You can shift it around.
We'll put it back in when it rotates.
This way, in the middle of this image.
It's supposed to rotate.
This is your choice.
This time I'd like to try to turn it in the middle.
It's a little sad.
Set the GLSL Input Extend Mode UV to Repeat
This way, it all comes out in a tiled shape.
That's what it means.
Then there's the scaling.
On the same page of The Book of Shaders, there is a description
Right here.
There's a place on this scale.
This is the formula for the matrix, even though it's a 3D one.
This is what the formula looks like if you make it 2D
I'd like to write this down.
mat2 scale(vec2 scale)
It comes as an argument.
return mat2(scale.x,
0.0, 0.0, scale.y)
This is the way it's done.
Something else.
Well, now we have a function for scaling.
We'll be able to use this in the main function as well
p *= scale() e.g. vec2's
If you make 1 or 2 here or there, you're going to reduce the size.
Put a fract function in here.
We'll put in the time.
Then the animation would look like this
A fract is a 0 to 1
Precisely because it takes a number between 0 and as close to 1 as possible.
It returns a number that is a decimal point lower than
It's a loop like this.
I'm trying to get a little bigger.
Like this.
I'm on three.
I'm going to try to reverse the direction for a moment.
I'm going to subtract.
It goes like this.
Let's see what's happening with this again with uv
The center is right here.
You can see that the uv values have increased
This is what I showed you first.
I got about the same thing.
Now you can play with it by adjusting various values.
That's all for this time.
About twice a month at TDSW.
We're running live streaming workshops on the weekend.
Tickets are available through Petix and Eventbrite!
We also use Patreon
There are currently three plans available
You can find these links in the video overview section of the video
Check it out if you'd like.
So thank you for watching.
If you like it, Good Button and
Please subscribe to our channel!
goodbye
[Music]